<website>
  <static title="News">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
    New <b>QuickFIX 1.8.0</b> is available! Please see the release
    <a href="quickfix/NEWS">notes</a>. 
    </p>
    <p>
    QuickFIX support contracts <a href="services.html">now available</a>!
    </p>
    ]]>
  </static>
  <static title="About">
    <![CDATA[
    <p>
    QuickFIX is a full-featured open source FIX engine, currently
    compatible with the FIX 4.0-4.4 spec. It runs on Windows, Linux,
    Solaris, FreeBSD and Mac OS X.  API's are available for C++,
    Java, .NET, and Python.
    </p>
    ]]>
  </static>
  
  <page title="About">
    <section title="About QuickFIX">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      QuickFIX is a full-featured open source FIX engine, currently
      compatible with the FIX 4.0-4.4 spec. It runs on Windows, Linux,
      Solaris, FreeBSD and Mac OS X.  API's are available for C++,
      Java, .NET, and Python.  Learn <a href="About QuickFIX.pdf">more</a>.
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
    <section title="About FIX">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      The Financial Information eXchange (FIX) Protocol is a
      "language" which defines specific kinds of electronic messages
      for communicating securities transactions between two parties.  
      FIX defines only the format of the messages and the
      session-level interaction between two applications. More
      information on FIX can be found at the 
      <a href="http://www.fixprotocol.org/">FIX protocol web site</a>.
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
    <section title="Scripting FIX">
      <![CDATA[
      <i>June 29, 2004</i>
      <p>
      Integration of FIX into a trading system is often viewed as a <b>big complicated thing</b>, and in large systems, it sometimes can be.  But does it always have to be?
      </p>
      <p>
      At it's core, FIX does something really simple. No matter how much someone may go on about "Enterprise Solutions", the fact is you just want to move data from one place to another.  Sometimes you need all the bells and whistles required by a large-scale deployment, but sometimes you just need to shove some data down the pipe.
      </p>
      <p>
      An interesting thing happened in the financial industry a couple of years ago. Traditionally based on C and C++, more firms began adopting Java as their primary development platform. Moving from C++ to Java is not interesting in itself.  What is interesting is the idea of CTO's shifting focus from pure execution speed, and beginning to concentrate more on rapid development.  They saw Java as a way to achieve this.
      </p>
      <p>
      Scripting languages like 
      <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org">Ruby</a> and <a href="http://www.python.org">Python</a> have proven themselves to be wonderfully robust rapid development environments. At the cost of execution speed, you can put together systems in days which could take weeks with higher maintenance languages like C++ or even Java. For processes that don't need to eke out every last CPU cycle, my hope and belief is that these languages will become adopted for more diverse tasks.  
      </p>
      <p>
      Although several nice libraries like <a href="http://www.quantlib.org">quantlib</a> have scripting interfaces through python, there are few options for connectivity.  Well, thanks to the magic of <a href="http://www.swig.org">SWIG</a>, this is changing.  As of version <i>1.8.0</i>, QuickFIX comes with a full-featured Python API.  Now you can take those "prototypes" you have implemented in python and connect them to real trading systems.  And since the core is still implemented in C++, you still retain many of the speed advantages over a pure python implementation.
      </p>
      <p>
      Next time someone dumps a list of trades in <b>Random File Format v.136.98b</b> that must be pushed over a FIX connection, you will have a proper tool to do this.  You can rapidly implement your automated trading strategies and forward test them on a live connection.  And heck, if it makes money, why re-implement it anyway.
      </p>
      <p>
      Replacing complexity with simplicity is my main motivator right now.  Less C++ and more scripting will make my life easier.  I can write more functionality with less scaffolding.  Spend time running code instead of compiling it.  What can I say?  The summer makes me lazy.  I'd rather do more in less time with less effort.  Isn't that why we invented computers to begin with?
      </p>
      <p>
      <i>Oren Miller</i><br/>
      <a href="mailto:oren@quickfixengine.org">oren@quickfixengine.org</a>
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
  <page title="Download">
    <section title="Source Code">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      <table>
	<tr>
          <td>
	    <b>Windows</b>
          </td>
	  <td>
	  </td>
	</tr>
        <tr>
          <td align="right">
            Source:
          </td>
          <td>
            <a
            href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/quickfix/quickfix-1.8.0.zip">
            quickfix-1.8.0.zip</a>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td align="right">
            Binary:
          </td>
          <td>
            <a
            href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/quickfix/quickfix-bin-1.8.0.zip">
            quickfix-bin-1.8.0.zip</a>
          </td>
        </tr>
	<tr>
          <td>
	    <b>Unix</b>
          </td>
	  <td>
	  </td>	
	</tr>
        <tr>
          <td align="right">
            Source:
          </td>
          <td>
            <a
            href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/quickfix/quickfix-1.8.0.tar.gz">
            quickfix-1.8.0.tar.gz</a>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      </p><br/>
      ]]>
    </section>
    <section title="External Tools">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
	Here is a list of <i>free</i> third party tools that can be used in conjunction
	with QuickFIX.  These utilities are in no way affiliated with QuickFIX 
	and are supported by their respective companies or organizations.
      </p>
      <p>
	<table border="1" width="100%">
          <tr>
            <td><b>Product</b></td>
            <td><b>Company</b></td>
            <td><b>Description</b></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><a href="http://www.ethereal.com/download.html">Ethereal</a></td>
            <td><a href="http://www.ethereal.com">Ethereal</a></td>
            <td>A very powerful and full featured network protocol analyzer which support hundred of protocols, including FIX.  Use this to sniff out all FIX traffic regardless of what FIX engine it originates from.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><a href="http://www.javtech.com/rc/fixionary.htm">FIXionary</a></td>
            <td><a href="http://www.javtech.com/rc/fixionary.htm">Javelin Technologies</a></td>
            <td>Interactively browse the FIX protocol specification through this java application. Much nicer then browsing through the massive word documents or XML dictionaries.  Can be downloaded or used online.</td>
          </tr>
	  <tr>
	    <td><a href="http://www.transacttools.net/ttportal/datadict/browser.jsp">FIX Data Dictionary</a></td>
	    <td><a href="http://www.transacttools.net/">transacttools</a></td>
	    <td>Similar to FIXionary, but lighter weight.  Only available online</td>
	  </tr>
	  <tr>
	    <td><a href="http://b2bits.com/fixopaedia/index.html">FIXopaedia</a></td>
	    <td><a href="http://www.b2bits.com/">b2bits</a></td>
	    <td>Another lightweght online FIX reference</td>
	  </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><a href="http://www.stunnel.org/download/">Stunnel</a></td>
	    <td><a href="http://www.stunnel.org">Stunnel.org</a></td>
	    <td>Allows you to encrypt arbitrary TCP connections inside SSL. Use this to encrypt your FIX sessions without need to modify you're application code.</td>
          </tr>
	</table>
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
  <page title="Documentation">
    <section title="Project/Code Documentation">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      Documentation is included with the QuickFIX distribution. You
      can also access it <a
      href="quickfix/doc/html/index.html">online</a>. We generate our 
      documentation with an open source product called 
      <a href="http://www.stack.nl/~dimitri/doxygen">Doxygen</a>  It
      is amazing. We highly recommend checking it out.
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
    <section title="Installing QuickFIX">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      You can also find help on how to 
      <a href="quickfix/doc/html/install.html">install QuickFIX</a>
      and run the acceptance tests.
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
    <section title="Protocol Documentation">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      For help with the FIX protocol itself, check out the 
      <a href="http://www.fixprotocol.org">FIX Protocol
      Homepage</a>. Of particular interest are the <a
      href="http://www.fixprotocol.org/cgi-bin/Spec.cgi?menu=4">specification
      documents</a> and the <a
      href="http://www.fixprotocol.org/cgi-bin/Menu.cgi?menu=700">discussion forums</a>
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
  <page title="MailingList">
    <section title="Subscriptions and Archives">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      <b>User Support</b>
      <br/>
      <i>quickfix-users@lists.sourceforge.net</i>
      <br/>
      <a href="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum=quickfix-users">Archive</a>
      | 
      <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/quickfix-users">Subscribe/Unsubscribe</a>
      <br/><br/>
      <b>Developer Support</b> [<i>most active</i>]
      <br/>
      <i>quickfix-developers@lists.sourceforge.net</i>
      <br/>
      <a href="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum=quickfix-developers">Archive</a> | 
      <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/quickfix-developers">Subscribe/Unsubscribe</a>
      <br/><br/>
      <b>Announcements</b>
      <br/>
      <i>quickfix-announce@lists.sourceforge.net</i>
      <br/>
      <a href="http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?forum=quickfix-announce">Archive</a> | 
      <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/quickfix-announce">Subscribe/Unsubscribe</a>
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
  <page title="XML">
    <section title="FIX Specification">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      We created a parser to go through the FIX specs and generated well formed XML versions. We use this XML version to generate most of the code for our FIX engine. Seeing as though it is so useful for us, we figured other people might be interested too.
      </p>
      <p>
      This is a <i>machine readable</i> version of the FIX
      specification. If you have been looking for such a thing, this
      is it!
      </p>
      <p>
      <li>FIX 4.0  <a href="FIX40.xml">xml</a>
                   <a href="FIX40.html">html</a>
      </li>
      <li>FIX 4.1  <a href="FIX41.xml">xml</a>
                   <a href="FIX41.html">html</a>
      </li>
      <li>FIX 4.2  <a href="FIX42.xml">xml</a>
                   <a href="FIX42.html">html</a>
      </li>
      <li>FIX 4.3  <a href="FIX43.xml">xml</a>
                   <a href="FIX43.html">html</a>
      </li>    
      <li>FIX 4.4  <a href="FIX44.xml">xml</a>
                   <a href="FIX44.html">html</a>
      </li>    
      </p>
      <p>
      The XML documents were then reformatted into small browsable HTML
      files using this <a href="fixtohtml.xsl">xsl stylesheet</a>
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
  <page title="Developers">
    <section title="QuickFIX Source Code">
      <![CDATA[
      <p>
      The source code for QuickFIX can be accessed by browsing the
      current <a
      href="http://cvs.sourceforge.net/cgi-bin/viewcvs.cgi/quickfix/">CVS</a> 
      tree.
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
    <section title="Anonymous CVS Access">
      <![CDATA[      
      <p>
      <u>login</u><br/>
      cvs -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.sourceforge.net:/cvsroot/quickfix login
      <br/><br/>
      <u>checkout</u><br/>
      cvs -z3 -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.sourceforge.net:/cvsroot/quickfix co quickfix
      </p>
      <p>
      When prompted for a password for anonymous, simply hit [return].
      </p>
      <p>
      More information about CVS access can be found at out
      SourceForge <a
      href="http://sourceforge.net/cvs/?group_id=37535">CVS page</a>
      </p>
      ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
  <page title="Services">
    <section title="Support and Consulting">
    <![CDATA[
     <p>
     <i>Connamara Systems</i> and <i>Macdonald and Associates</i> <a href="PressRelease_QuickFIX_Support.pdf">have teamed up</a> to provide formal QuickFIX support, consulting, and training.  Both these companies have been very supportive of the QuickFIX project.  We are pleased to recognize them as preferred service providers.
     </p>
     <p>
     If you are interested in learning about QuickFIX, FIX, and trading related services, just email us at <a href="mailto:ask@quickfixengine.org">ask@quickfixengine.org</a>. Please leave your contact information such as email or a telephone number where you can be reached.
     </p>
     <hr/>
    ]]>
    </section>
    <section>
    <![CDATA[
      <a href="http://www.connamara.com"><IMG src="img/connamara.gif" width="210" height="33" border="0" alt="Connamara Logo"></a>
     <p>With offices in Chicago and New Delhi, Connamara Systems, LLC provides FIX consulting, QuickFIX support and custom trading systems development service to the equities and derivatives trading industries. Connamara was an initial collaborator in the creation of QuickFIX and continues to contribute to the enhancements and maintenance of the engine.  More information can be found at <a href="http://www.connamara.com">www.connamara.com</a></p>
    ]]>
    </section>
    <section>
    <![CDATA[
      <a href="http://www.macd.com"><IMG src="img/macd.gif" width="210" height="60" border="0" alt="Macdonald Associates Logo"></a>
     <p>Macdonald Associates Ltd., founded in 1983, has a pan-European presence covering the UK, Switzerland and Germany. The company has a range of trading products in the equity and fixed income markets and also offers training and consulting to financial institutions.  Macdonald has been active in the QuickFIX community and uses QuickFIX within their own product line. For more details, see <a href="http://www.macd.com">www.macd.com</a> or email <a href="mailto:george.macdonald@macd.com">george.macdonald@macd.com</a></p>
    ]]>
    </section>
  </page>
  
</website>
